const eng1 = {
  data: [
    {
      id: 1,
      questionNub: 1,
      question: "When did Christopher Marlowe get his first degree?",
      section:
        "Read the following passage and answer the questions below:\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nChristopher Marlowe, the son of Marlowe who is described as the clerk of St Mary's in the city of Canterbury, was born in 1564. He received his early education at The King's School in that city. He took the degrees of B.A. and M.A. in 1583 and 1587 respectively from Cambridge University. He started writing poems and became a renowned dramatist in the Admiral's Company.\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nMarlowe is known as one of the university wits, a group of dramatists along with Robert Greene, Thomas Nash, and George Peele. Marlowe is considered the greatest precursor to Shakespeare. When Marlowe came upon the English stage, the nature of drama was undeveloped. The verses in the dramas were lifeless. But Marlowe gave English drama an appropriate meter, diction, and method. It is really a matter of speculation what kind of greatness he would have achieved if his life had not been terminated (C++) in a duel after a brawl in a tavern (inn).\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nThe literary life of Marlowe had a short span, from 1587 to 1593. During this period, he wrote five plays which were all tragedies as he had no comic vein. His tragedies like Dr Faustus, The Jew of Malta, and Edward Il are rated as some of the best works of the Elizabethan age. He also wrote an unfinished poem Hero and Leander and translated some parts of Ovid's (a Roman Poet) elegies.\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nMarlowe's subjects are mostly heroic which appeals to the imagination of the play-goers. His heroes epitomize the spirit of the Renaissance. Each of them embodies a passion and tries to achieve lies in his development of the blank verse. He put it at any cost. But Marlowe's chief contribution aside from the old rhyming lines then employed in the plays and used blank verse. Thus, the language of drama was brought closer to real life and drama was made ready for Shakespeare (1564-1616) to improve upon it. It is rightly said, \"No Marlowe, no Shakespeare\".\u003Cbr\u003E\n&nbsp;",
      option: {
        a: "1587",
        b: "1583",
        c: "1593",
        d: "1564",
      },
      category: "",
      image: "",
      answer: "b",
      solution: "",
      examtype: "utme",
      examyear: "2021",
    },
    {
      id: 2,
      questionNub: 2,
      question: "How long was Christopher Marlowe's literary life?",
      section:
        "Read the following passage and answer the questions below:\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nChristopher Marlowe, the son of Marlowe who is described as the clerk of St Mary's in the city of Canterbury, was born in 1564. He received his early education at The King's School in that city. He took the degrees of B.A. and M.A. in 1583 and 1587 respectively from Cambridge University. He started writing poems and became a renowned dramatist in the Admiral's Company.\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nMarlowe is known as one of the university wits, a group of dramatists along with Robert Greene, Thomas Nash, and George Peele. Marlowe is considered the greatest precursor to Shakespeare. When Marlowe came upon the English stage, the nature of drama was undeveloped. The verses in the dramas were lifeless. But Marlowe gave English drama an appropriate meter, diction, and method. It is really a matter of speculation what kind of greatness he would have achieved if his life had not been terminated (C++) in a duel after a brawl in a tavern (inn).\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nThe literary life of Marlowe had a short span, from 1587 to 1593. During this period, he wrote five plays which were all tragedies as he had no comic vein. His tragedies like Dr Faustus, The Jew of Malta, and Edward Il are rated as some of the best works of the Elizabethan age. He also wrote an unfinished poem Hero and Leander and translated some parts of Ovid's (a Roman Poet) elegies.\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nMarlowe's subjects are mostly heroic which appeals to the imagination of the play-goers. His heroes epitomize the spirit of the Renaissance. Each of them embodies a passion and tries to achieve lies in his development of the blank verse. He put it at any cost. But Marlowe's chief contribution aside from the old rhyming lines then employed in the plays and used blank verse. Thus, the language of drama was brought closer to real life and drama was made ready for Shakespeare (1564-1616) to improve upon it. It is rightly said, \"No Marlowe, no Shakespeare\".\u003Cbr\u003E\n&nbsp;",
      option: {
        a: "6 years",
        b: "60 years",
        c: "10 years",
        d: "5 years",
      },
      category: "",
      image: "",
      answer: "d",
      solution: "",
      examtype: "utme",
      examyear: "2021",
    },
    {
      id: 3,
      questionNub: 3,
      question:
        "What is the title of one of Christopher Marlowe's renowned tragedies mentioned in the passage?",
      section:
        "Read the following passage and answer the questions below:\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nChristopher Marlowe, the son of Marlowe who is described as the clerk of St Mary's in the city of Canterbury, was born in 1564. He received his early education at The King's School in that city. He took the degrees of B.A. and M.A. in 1583 and 1587 respectively from Cambridge University. He started writing poems and became a renowned dramatist in the Admiral's Company.\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nMarlowe is known as one of the university wits, a group of dramatists along with Robert Greene, Thomas Nash, and George Peele. Marlowe is considered the greatest precursor to Shakespeare. When Marlowe came upon the English stage, the nature of drama was undeveloped. The verses in the dramas were lifeless. But Marlowe gave English drama an appropriate meter, diction, and method. It is really a matter of speculation what kind of greatness he would have achieved if his life had not been terminated (C++) in a duel after a brawl in a tavern (inn).\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nThe literary life of Marlowe had a short span, from 1587 to 1593. During this period, he wrote five plays which were all tragedies as he had no comic vein. His tragedies like Dr Faustus, The Jew of Malta, and Edward Il are rated as some of the best works of the Elizabethan age. He also wrote an unfinished poem Hero and Leander and translated some parts of Ovid's (a Roman Poet) elegies.\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nMarlowe's subjects are mostly heroic which appeals to the imagination of the play-goers. His heroes epitomize the spirit of the Renaissance. Each of them embodies a passion and tries to achieve lies in his development of the blank verse. He put it at any cost. But Marlowe's chief contribution aside from the old rhyming lines then employed in the plays and used blank verse. Thus, the language of drama was brought closer to real life and drama was made ready for Shakespeare (1564-1616) to improve upon it. It is rightly said, \"No Marlowe, no Shakespeare\".\u003Cbr\u003E\n&nbsp;",
      option: {
        a: "Dr Faustus",
        b: "The Tempest",
        c: "Romeo and Juliet",
        d: "Hamlet",
      },
      category: "",
      image: "",
      answer: "a",
      solution: "",
      examtype: "utme",
      examyear: "2021",
    },
    {
      id: 4,
      questionNub: 4,
      question:
        "Which university did Christopher Marlowe attend to obtain his degrees?",
      section:
        "Read the following passage and answer the questions below:\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nChristopher Marlowe, the son of Marlowe who is described as the clerk of St Mary's in the city of Canterbury, was born in 1564. He received his early education at The King's School in that city. He took the degrees of B.A. and M.A. in 1583 and 1587 respectively from Cambridge University. He started writing poems and became a renowned dramatist in the Admiral's Company.\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nMarlowe is known as one of the university wits, a group of dramatists along with Robert Greene, Thomas Nash, and George Peele. Marlowe is considered the greatest precursor to Shakespeare. When Marlowe came upon the English stage, the nature of drama was undeveloped. The verses in the dramas were lifeless. But Marlowe gave English drama an appropriate meter, diction, and method. It is really a matter of speculation what kind of greatness he would have achieved if his life had not been terminated (C++) in a duel after a brawl in a tavern (inn).\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nThe literary life of Marlowe had a short span, from 1587 to 1593. During this period, he wrote five plays which were all tragedies as he had no comic vein. His tragedies like Dr Faustus, The Jew of Malta, and Edward Il are rated as some of the best works of the Elizabethan age. He also wrote an unfinished poem Hero and Leander and translated some parts of Ovid's (a Roman Poet) elegies.\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nMarlowe's subjects are mostly heroic which appeals to the imagination of the play-goers. His heroes epitomize the spirit of the Renaissance. Each of them embodies a passion and tries to achieve lies in his development of the blank verse. He put it at any cost. But Marlowe's chief contribution aside from the old rhyming lines then employed in the plays and used blank verse. Thus, the language of drama was brought closer to real life and drama was made ready for Shakespeare (1564-1616) to improve upon it. It is rightly said, \"No Marlowe, no Shakespeare\".\u003Cbr\u003E\n&nbsp;",
      option: {
        a: "Oxford University",
        b: "Harvard University",
        c: "Cambridge University",
        d: "Yale University",
      },
      category: "",
      image: "",
      answer: "c",
      solution: "",
      examtype: "utme",
      examyear: "2021",
    },
    {
      id: 5,
      questionNub: 5,
      question:
        "Which group of dramatists is Christopher Marlowe associated with?",
      section:
        "Read the following passage and answer the questions below:\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nChristopher Marlowe, the son of Marlowe who is described as the clerk of St Mary's in the city of Canterbury, was born in 1564. He received his early education at The King's School in that city. He took the degrees of B.A. and M.A. in 1583 and 1587 respectively from Cambridge University. He started writing poems and became a renowned dramatist in the Admiral's Company.\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nMarlowe is known as one of the university wits, a group of dramatists along with Robert Greene, Thomas Nash, and George Peele. Marlowe is considered the greatest precursor to Shakespeare. When Marlowe came upon the English stage, the nature of drama was undeveloped. The verses in the dramas were lifeless. But Marlowe gave English drama an appropriate meter, diction, and method. It is really a matter of speculation what kind of greatness he would have achieved if his life had not been terminated (C++) in a duel after a brawl in a tavern (inn).\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nThe literary life of Marlowe had a short span, from 1587 to 1593. During this period, he wrote five plays which were all tragedies as he had no comic vein. His tragedies like Dr Faustus, The Jew of Malta, and Edward Il are rated as some of the best works of the Elizabethan age. He also wrote an unfinished poem Hero and Leander and translated some parts of Ovid's (a Roman Poet) elegies.\u003Cbr\u003E\n\u003Cbr\u003E\nMarlowe's subjects are mostly heroic which appeals to the imagination of the play-goers. His heroes epitomize the spirit of the Renaissance. Each of them embodies a passion and tries to achieve lies in his development of the blank verse. He put it at any cost. But Marlowe's chief contribution aside from the old rhyming lines then employed in the plays and used blank verse. Thus, the language of drama was brought closer to real life and drama was made ready for Shakespeare (1564-1616) to improve upon it. It is rightly said, \"No Marlowe, no Shakespeare\".\u003Cbr\u003E\n&nbsp;",
      option: {
        a: "The Romantic Poets",
        b: "The Metaphysical Poets",
        c: "The University Wits",
        d: "The Pre-Raphaelites",
      },
      category: "",
      image: "",
      answer: "c",
      solution: "",
      examtype: "utme",
      examyear: "2021",
    },
    {
      id: 6,
      questionNub: 6,
      question:
        "In question number 11&nbsp;above choose the best option from letters A- E&nbsp;that best complete the gap",
      section:
        "In the passage below, the numbered gaps (11-20) indicate missing words. From the options lettered A- E&nbsp;the most appropriate option.The head of the -11- is called the queen bee. She is -12-than the rest of the bees. Her main task in the colony is to lay eggs. Most of the other bees are the -13- bees. These bees collect nectar and -14- from flowers. The nectar that is&nbsp;carried by the worker bees is deposited on the hive and then -15- into honey. The worker bees also help to look after the young bees. As soon as they are -16-, the worker bees feed the young bees with pollen and nectar. The third type of bee found in the colony is the -17- or male bee. The main task of such a bee is to -18- with a new queen. The queen bee has a life span of about three years. During this period, she would have -19- more than half a million eggs. When the queen bee is dying, a new queen would be groomed. This new queen will eventually take over the duties of the old queen when the -20- dies.",
      option: {
        a: "house",
        b: "colony",
        c: "settlement",
        d: "abode",
        e: "habitat",
      },
      category: "",
      image: "",
      answer: "b",
      solution: "",
      examtype: "utme",
      examyear: "2021",
    },
    {
      id: 7,
      questionNub: 7,
      question:
        "In question number 12&nbsp;above choose the best option from letters A- E&nbsp;that best complete the gap",
      section:
        "In the passage below, the numbered gaps (11-20) indicate missing words. From the options lettered A- E&nbsp;the most appropriate option.The head of the -11- is called the queen bee. She is -12-than the rest of the bees. Her main task in the colony is to lay eggs. Most of the other bees are the -13- bees. These bees collect nectar and -14- from flowers. The nectar that is&nbsp;carried by the worker bees is deposited on the hive and then -15- into honey. The worker bees also help to look after the young bees. As soon as they are -16-, the worker bees feed the young bees with pollen and nectar. The third type of bee found in the colony is the -17- or male bee. The main task of such a bee is to -18- with a new queen. The queen bee has a life span of about three years. During this period, she would have -19- more than half a million eggs. When the queen bee is dying, a new queen would be groomed. This new queen will eventually take over the duties of the old queen when the -20- dies.",
      option: {
        a: "larger",
        b: "enormous",
        c: "thicker",
        d: "older",
        e: "wiser",
      },
      category: "",
      image: "",
      answer: "a",
      solution: "",
      examtype: "utme",
      examyear: "2021",
    },
    {
      id: 8,
      questionNub: 8,
      question:
        "In question number 13&nbsp;above choose the best option from letters A- E&nbsp;that best complete the gap",
      section:
        "In the passage below, the numbered gaps (11-20) indicate missing words. From the options lettered A- E&nbsp;the most appropriate option.The head of the -11- is called the queen bee. She is -12-than the rest of the bees. Her main task in the colony is to lay eggs. Most of the other bees are the -13- bees. These bees collect nectar and -14- from flowers. The nectar that is&nbsp;carried by the worker bees is deposited on the hive and then -15- into honey. The worker bees also help to look after the young bees. As soon as they are -16-, the worker bees feed the young bees with pollen and nectar. The third type of bee found in the colony is the -17- or male bee. The main task of such a bee is to -18- with a new queen. The queen bee has a life span of about three years. During this period, she would have -19- more than half a million eggs. When the queen bee is dying, a new queen would be groomed. This new queen will eventually take over the duties of the old queen when the -20- dies.",
      option: {
        a: "servant",
        b: "maid",
        c: "workers",
        d: "errand",
      },
      category: "",
      image: "",
      answer: "c",
      solution: "",
      examtype: "utme",
      examyear: "2021",
    },
    {
      id: 9,
      questionNub: 9,
      question:
        "In question number 14&nbsp;above choose the best option from letters A- E&nbsp;that best complete the gap",
      section:
        "In the passage below, the numbered gaps (11-20) indicate missing words. From the options lettered A- E&nbsp;the most appropriate option.The head of the -11- is called the queen bee. She is -12-than the rest of the bees. Her main task in the colony is to lay eggs. Most of the other bees are the -13- bees. These bees collect nectar and -14- from flowers. The nectar that is&nbsp;carried by the worker bees is deposited on the hive and then -15- into honey. The worker bees also help to look after the young bees. As soon as they are -16-, the worker bees feed the young bees with pollen and nectar. The third type of bee found in the colony is the -17- or male bee. The main task of such a bee is to -18- with a new queen. The queen bee has a life span of about three years. During this period, she would have -19- more than half a million eggs. When the queen bee is dying, a new queen would be groomed. This new queen will eventually take over the duties of the old queen when the -20- dies.",
      option: {
        a: "fruits",
        b: "seed",
        c: "pollen",
        d: "grains",
        e: "leaves",
      },
      category: "",
      image: "",
      answer: "c",
      solution: "",
      examtype: "utme",
      examyear: "2021",
    },
    {
      id: 10,
      questionNub: 10,
      question:
        "In question number 15&nbsp;above choose the best option from letters A- E&nbsp;that best complete the gap",
      section:
        "In the passage below, the numbered gaps (11-20) indicate missing words. From the options lettered A- E&nbsp;the most appropriate option.The head of the -11- is called the queen bee. She is -12-than the rest of the bees. Her main task in the colony is to lay eggs. Most of the other bees are the -13- bees. These bees collect nectar and -14- from flowers. The nectar that is&nbsp;carried by the worker bees is deposited on the hive and then -15- into honey. The worker bees also help to look after the young bees. As soon as they are -16-, the worker bees feed the young bees with pollen and nectar. The third type of bee found in the colony is the -17- or male bee. The main task of such a bee is to -18- with a new queen. The queen bee has a life span of about three years. During this period, she would have -19- more than half a million eggs. When the queen bee is dying, a new queen would be groomed. This new queen will eventually take over the duties of the old queen when the -20- dies.",
      option: {
        a: "filtered",
        b: "converted",
        c: "refined",
        d: "cooked",
        e: "baked",
      },
      category: "",
      image: "",
      answer: "c",
      solution: "",
      examtype: "utme",
      examyear: "2021",
    },
    {
      id: 11,
      questionNub: 11,
      question: "What did the author of the book study?\u003Cbr\u003E\n&nbsp;",
      section:
        '\u003Cstrong\u003EThis question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli\'s novel\u003C/strong\u003E, "The Life Changer"',
      option: {
        a: "B.Sc (Ed) Mathematics",
        b: "B.A English Language",
        c: "B.A Literary Studies",
        d: "BSc Political Science",
      },
      category: "",
      image: "",
      answer: "c",
      solution: "",
      examtype: "utme",
      examyear: "2021",
    },
    {
      id: 12,
      questionNub: 12,
      question: "The book described Talle&nbsp;as a?",
      section:
        '\u003Cstrong\u003EThis question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli\'s novel\u003C/strong\u003E, "The Life Changer"',
      option: {
        a: "The precious child",
        b: "The quiet one",
        c: "The friendly child",
        d: "the holy child",
      },
      category: "",
      image: "",
      answer: "b",
      solution: "",
      examtype: "utme",
      examyear: "2021",
    },
    {
      id: 13,
      questionNub: 13,
      question: "Who was Omar's&nbsp;immediate sister?",
      section:
        '\u003Cstrong\u003EThis question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli\'s novel\u003C/strong\u003E, "The Life Changer"',
      option: {
        a: "Ummi",
        b: "Omar",
        c: "Salma",
        d: "Teemah",
      },
      category: "",
      image: "",
      answer: "c",
      solution: "",
      examtype: "utme",
      examyear: "2021",
    },
    {
      id: 14,
      questionNub: 14,
      question:
        "Ummi's husband wanted to study law but the providence chose that he study _____",
      section:
        '\u003Cstrong\u003EThis question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli\'s novel\u003C/strong\u003E, "The Life Changer"',
      option: {
        a: "commerce",
        b: "accounting",
        c: "law",
        d: "history",
      },
      category: "",
      image: "",
      answer: "b",
      solution: "",
      examtype: "utme",
      examyear: "2021",
    },
    {
      id: 15,
      questionNub: 15,
      question: "The full meaning of IPO is ______",
      section:
        '\u003Cstrong\u003EThis question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli\'s novel\u003C/strong\u003E, "The Life Changer"',
      option: {
        a: "Independent Police Officer",
        b: "International Police Officer",
        c: "Investigating Police Officer",
        d: "Investigative Police Officer",
      },
      category: "",
      image: "",
      answer: "d",
      solution: "",
      examtype: "utme",
      examyear: "2021",
    },
  ],
};
